





Business Consultant seeking roles in Business Analysis, Project Management, Workflow Analysis, Effort Estimation, Client Management, Software Testing, Agile Methodology, Stakeholder Management, SQL, MS Visio, HP Quality Center



Current Designation: Business Consultant

Current Company: Wells Frago India Pvt. Ltd.
Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad

 $Pref.\ Location: \textbf{Bengaluru} \ / \ \textbf{Bangalore}, \textbf{Pune}, \textbf{Hyderabad}$

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming / Maintenance

Role: Business Analyst

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Business Consultant, Business Analyst, Business Analysis, Project Management, Workflow Analysis, Effort Estimation, Client Management, Software Testing, Agile Methodology, Stakeholder Management, SQL, MS Visio, HP Quality

Total Experience: 9 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Notice Period: 1 Month

Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Electronics/Telecommunication]

Center

Verified: Email - id

Last Active: 18-Jan-21 Last Modified: 18-Jan-21

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Summary

A competent and experienced business analyst with 6+ year of experience in managing multi-disciplinary teams of varying sizes and complex program to work. Ability to build strong relationships with all stakeholders and to turn proposals into reality

Active involvement in all phases of STLC, SDLC such as Analysis, Design, Development, Integration, Implementation and Maintenance

Design Business Workflow/ Process flow diagrams, User Stories preparation and define Use Case Specifications Analyzing business needs, gathering requirements, planning, organizing, documenting, and testing software applications Creating Business Requirement Document, Functional Specifications, Software Requirement Specifications, Scope, Timelines for a Project, Effort Estimations, Traceability Matrix.

Coordinate with stakeholders on gathering and understanding business needs of the clients.

Work Experience

Wells Frago India Pvt. Ltd. as Business Consultant Jan 2014 to Till Date

Wells Frago India Pvt. Ltd. Aug 2018-till date Project: Payments Contributions:

Business System Consultant, act as liaison between project management, technology teams and business stakeholders.

Daily stand up calls and discussions have been made to know the status of the items in the current sprint and for the future sprints.

Responsible for preparing BRD, FSD, RTM, User Stories and RACI preparation

Defined and documented clear and complete detailed business requirements and functional specifications using the SDLC methodology from the Business team.

Developed, and presented project demos and trained to pertinent business groups.

Continuous testing of the Application using different client scenarios

Perform GAP analysis of business rules, business and system process flows, user administration, and requirements.

Manages the Product Backlog for a product and working along with the Technical Delivery Manager to prioritize the requirements for defining and managing the scope and sprints for a project

Identify, effectively communicate, and resolve project issues and risks. Effectively communicate project status to project stakeholders

Involved in different tasks associated with Knowledge Areas: Requirement Life Cycle Management, Requirements Analysis and Design Documents, Elicitation, Solution Assessment & Validation Stakeholder Management, Team effort tracking and reports preparation.

Tech Mahindra Pvt. Ltd. as Senior Software Test Engineer

1

Important

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld.

Mar 2011 to Dec 2013

Contributions:

Analyzing the requirements from EDD and identify test scenarios for preparing Test Plan.

Preparing test cases, debugging and executing test cases.

Preparing and maintaining test data as per the requirement.

Sending daily execution report taken from QC. Involved in identifying test cases for regression and for automation. Involved in Defect tracking and retesting.

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E (Electronics/Telecommunication) from Punjab Technical University (PTU) in 2010

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used	Experience
User Stories		5 Year(s)
use cases		5 Year(s)
Requirements Management		5 Year(s)
Requirement GATHERING		5 Year(s)
BUSINESS ANALYSIS		6 Year(s) 2 Month(s)
Certified Scrum Master		4 Year(s)
Certified ISTQB Advanced		
JIRA		4 Year(s)
CONFLUENCE		2 Year(s)
MS OFFICE		
HP-QC, ALM 12.1		
Balsamiq tool, Lucidchart, Visio		

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General Physically Challenged: No Job Type: Permanent Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

 ${\it Careers-About\,Us-Clients-Terms\,\&\,Conditions-FAQ's-Contact\,Us-Report\,a\,Problem-Site\,Map-Resources}$ Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.